cubcadet.com 2017-06-24

# Cub Cadet: Riding Lawn Mowers, Lawn Tractors & Snowblowers

**Effective Date: September 8, 2015**

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Cub Cadet LLC, including each of its subsidiaries and/or affiliates, having a principal place of business located at 5903 Grafton Road, Valley City, Ohio 44280 (“Cub Cadet”) is committed to protecting the privacy and security of personal information. As part of normal business activities, we may collect and store personal information regarding customers, employees and associates, suppliers, and distributors. Personal information may be collected, transferred, and stored on servers located in any country in which we do business.

The following persons or entities may have access to the information that you provide to Cub Cadet: Cub Cadet, our employees and associates; Cub Cadet authorized sales and service centers; and service providers who assist us with archival, auditing, accounting, legal, business consulting, and website or technology services. Cub Cadet will not need your consent for the transmission of your personal information to the foregoing persons or entities. Please bear in mind that Cub Cadet and our service providers will take reasonable care to protect data and limit access only to associates who have a legitimate business reason to view the data. All parties who have access to your information are required to keep the information confidential and may not use it for any purpose other than to provide you services within the normal business activities of Cub Cadet and its authorized sales and service centers.

This policy (the “Policy”) applies to all personal information that is provided to Cub Cadet in any form or medium, and may be amended from time to time. If our information practices change at some time in the future, we will post the policy changes here as notification and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back to our website periodically.

**Our Commitment to Children's Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we know are under the age of 13. If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information, a parent/guardian may follow the procedures below to access a child's information and to request the information be deleted from our records. Following such a request, we will make reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from our records.

**General Principals**

**_NOTICE_**

**_What Information Do We Collect_**

Cub Cadet may collect personal information online, in person, over the phone or through the mail. This personal information may include: (i) contact information (including: name, address, phone number, and e-mail address), serial and model number of products purchased, information about your shopping preferences and purchases, survey information (which may include: age, household description, lawn care/outdoor power product ownership/purchase information, etc.), purchase orders, and employment information (i.e. job title, location, etc.), (ii) financial or economic information as your credit card or debit card information and  invoices. Personal Information does not include information that is publicly available, such as a person's name, address and phone number listed in a directory.

Please bear in mind that Cub Cadet will require your express consent prior the collection of your financial or economic information. 

**_Why We Collect Personal Information_**

We collect Personal Information for the following purposes which give origin to and are considered necessary for the existence, maintenance and compliance of the legal relationship whether existent or possible between Cub Cadet and you: (i) for commercial reasons, including: fulfilling requests for products, administering product programs and warranties, responding to inquiries about our offerings, to track customer preferences, to communicate with customers regarding their account with us, and (ii) in case you are an employee of Cub Cadet, your Personal Information will be used for employment purposes (i.e. keeping updated organizational information, making employment related decisions, employee training, employment investigations, etc.). 

In addition, and subject to your authorization, your personal information shall be used to: marketing new products and services, to notify and offer our new products, programs or services.

Cub Cadet limits the collection and use of personal information to what is reasonably necessary to fulfill the purpose for which the personal information is collected. The personal information we collect will only be used for the purposes identified at the time of collection or as outlined in this Policy. 

**_CHOICE_**

If at any time you do not wish to continue receiving information from us or you would like to withdraw the personal information you have previously disclosed, you can ask that your personal information be removed from our records and/or consent withdrawn. You can do so by submitting a request to:

Cub Cadet LLC

Information Privacy Department

P.O. Box 368022

Cleveland, OH  44136

Email: infoprivacy@cubcadet.com

Unless otherwise authorized by the individual, Cub Cadet will not disclose personal information to a third party for use in a manner incompatible with the purpose for which it was originally collected. However, an individual may not opt out of the transfer of his or her personal information which is transferred by Cub Cadet to a third party for the purpose of (1) meeting applicable legal requirements or (2) permitting the legitimate interests of Cub Cadet in making promotions, appointments, or other employment decisions. For certain more sensitive personal information (which may include race, gender, religion, medical information, etc.) Cub Cadet will provide an affirmative or explicit (opt in) choice if the personal information is to be disclosed to a third party for use in a manner incompatible with the purpose for which it was collected.

**_ONWARD TRANSFER_**

Cub Cadet will keep your personal information private and will not disclose it to other parties, unless you have granted Cub Cadet permission to transfer your personal information or such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with federal or state law, a court order or other legal process; (b) protect our rights or property; (c) enforce any of our Terms and Conditions of Use; or (d) in connection with the sale of assets and/or the company. Prior to disclosing personal information to a third party, Cub Cadet will apply the aforementioned Notice and Choice principles. Cub Cadet will also confirm that any third party subscribes to these principles and will enter into a written agreement with such third party requiring that the third party provide at least the same level of privacy protection provided by Cub Cadet.

**_SECURITY_**

No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Accordingly, despite our efforts to protect personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us online. You transmit all such information at your own risk.

However, once we receive your transmission, we take reasonable measures to ensure that personal information is safeguarded at all times. We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of personal information under our control. Our data networks are secured and protected by firewalls and other safeguards. In addition to technological measures, we also ensure that personal information stored on our premises or stored by our third parties, is secured by other means, including restricting access and using locked and secured storage units.

In the event of a breach of our systems and unless a law enforcement agency informs us that notification would impede a criminal investigation, you will be notified of any unencrypted personal information that was or was reasonably believed to have been acquired by an unauthorized person as soon as reasonably possible. 

**_DATA INTEGRITY_**

Cub Cadet uses personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently authorized. To the extent necessary for those purposes, Cub Cadet will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is accurate, current, complete, and reliable for its intended use.

**_ACCESS, RECTIFICATION, SUPPRESSION AND REJECTION_**

As owner of the personal information you provide us with, you are entitled to access the personal information we possess and the details of the processing of such information; rectify the information whenever it is incomplete or imprecise; suppress the information if you deem it is not required for the purposes set forth herein, or if it is being used for purposes not consented; or otherwise, object to the processing of the personal information provided for specific objectives. 

You may update, remove, or correct your personal information on record with us by logging into your account (if applicable), sending an e-mail to infoprivacy@cubcadet.com, or by writing us at Cub Cadet LLC, Information Privacy Department, P.O. Box 368022, Cleveland, OH  44136\.  To protect your privacy and security, we also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. We will respond to all inquiries with respect to updating, removing, or correcting your personal information within a reasonable time.

Should you wish to exercise your right of access, rectification, suppression and/or objection of personal information processing, or if you have any doubts or inquiries in connection with such, you may contact our Information Privacy Department at the address and/or email provided in our contact details.

Any application for the exercise of the aforementioned rights must necessarily indicate and include: i) your name and domicile, ii) copy of your official ID (passport, voter’s ID, driver’s license), iii) a clear and precise description of the personal information you wish to access, rectify, suppress or object and any other component which facilitates the obtainment of your data, as well as iv) any other requirement set forth in terms of the applicable law.

Cub Cadet shall respond to any complete application within 20 calendar days or the maximum term permitted by the applicable law. Cub Cadet’s reply shall indicate if the application for access, rectification, cancellation or objection is appropriate and, in such case, Cub Cadet shall effect its decision within the following 15 calendar days or the maximum term permitted by the applicable law to the date in which the answer was delivered to the owner of the personal information or to his or her representative. The terms may be extended pursuant to the applicable provisions. If you are exercising your right of access, Cub Cadet may provide you with electronic copies of your personal information. 

**_LIMIT USE OR DISCLOSURE_**

You are entitled to, at any time, to limit the use or disclosure of your personal information for the purposes that are not necessary for our legal relationship.  If you wish to limit the use of your personal information, please contact our Information Privacy Department by mail or e-mail, stating the purposes for which you wish to limit the use or disclosure of your personal information. 

Additionally, you may register with public registries of consumers in order to avoid having unwanted information sent to you. For additional information please consult your national or local authority for consumer protection. 

**_CONSENT REVOCATION_**

You may, at any time, revoke your consent granted for the processing of your personal information by contacting our Information Privacy Department, by cancelling your user profile in our website, calling our telephone number, sending an email or appearing personally in our offices and advising us of your situation. However, in the event you revoke your consent for the treatment of your personal data (including financial and economic), we may not be able to continue our legal relationship.

**_ENFORCEMENT_**

Cub Cadet uses a self-assessment approach to ensure compliance with this Policy. This includes a periodic assessment to verify the Policy is accurate and being adhered to. If you have concerns, contact us by e-mail at infoprivacy@cubcadet.com, or by writing us at Cub Cadet LLC, Information Privacy Department, P.O. Box 368022, Cleveland, OH  44136, and Cub Cadet will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information.

**cubcadet.com**

**_REGISTRATION_**

Cubcadet.com has no registration requirement. At cubcadet.com, you have the choice to create an account. This will enable you to register your recently purchased product, place additional orders, rate and review our products, etc. If you choose not to register, you will be able to access all areas of cubcadet.com that do not require registration.

Whether you choose to register when you visit cubcadet.com or not we automatically track and collect the following anonymous information that does not personally identify you but is helpful for administering the site, analyzing trends, tracking user movements, and gathering broad demographic information for aggregate use: (a) IP address; (b) domain name; (c) type of computer; and (d) type of Web browser. 

The collection, processing, and the use of data collected during the registration process requires your consent. This consent may be declared electronically and as noted above you may withdraw your consent at any time as set out in the _Choice_ and _Access Rectification, Suppression and Rejection_ sections of this Policy. 

**_COOKIES_**

Cubcadet.com utilizes cookies for several purposes, including the storage of information required to determine how to properly deliver content to your machine. A cookie is provided to all visitors to cubcadet.com, regardless of whether you create an account.

A cookie is a small piece of information that a Web server stores temporarily using your Web browser and then later retrieves. A cookie is not a way for a Web server to access and find out private information about you. However, once you choose to furnish a website with personal information, for example, by registering at one of our websites, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

The use of cookies is relatively standard and you will likely find them used on most other Web sites. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can customize the settings on your browser either to notify you when you receive a cookie or to refuse to accept cookies. Disabling cookies for this website will not impact your ability to use its features or view its content, but you may not be able to take advantage of the website’s personalization features.

**_ONLINE BEHAVIORAL ADVERTISING_**

Cubcadet.com engages in Online Behavioral Advertising (OBA) in accordance with the guidelines set forth by the Digital Advertising Alliance.  Cub Cadet uses anonymous cookies to track information on your browsing history on cubcadet.com, and third-party advertising networks use the information to serve ads to you on Cub Cadet's behalf on other sites throughout the Internet. These cookies do not contain personally identifiable information, nor are they linked to any personal information collected by Cub Cadet.

You may opt-out of third-party advertising networks by using the Network Advertising Initiative's (NAI's) multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. These opt-outs are valid only for the computer and browser combination used to opt-out. Clearing cookies will remove these opt-outs since they stored in cookies. 

If you opt-out of an NAI third-party advertising network, you will no longer receive ads based on your browsing history from that network. You may, however, continue to receive generalized online advertising. 

**_NOTICE TO PERSONS ACCESSING THIS WEBSITE OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES_**

If you reside outside the United States, any information you provide to us through this website may be transferred out of your country and into the United States to Cub Cadet and/or any other company that belongs to Cub Cadet’s economic group.  We do not need additional consent for this transfer. If you do not want your personal information to leave your country, please do not submit that information through this website. By providing personal information, you explicitly consent to the transfer of your information to the United States. You also consent to the application of U.S. law, as well as local law, to our processing your personal information.

**_LIMITATIONS_**

Cub Cadet is responsible for its own content offered on this website. All of the content has been carefully checked and will be complemented and updated regularly. However, Cub Cadet does not guarantee that this content is completely accurate or up to date.  

In addition, links to external internet sites are available on this website. Cub Cadet is not responsible for the content or design of these websites and is thus, not liable for the accuracy, completeness or quality of the information available there.  Moreover, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. Please refer to the privacy policies of each website that you visit. 

**_CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY_**

From time to time, Cub Cadet may use customer information for new purposes not previously disclosed in this privacy Policy. If our information practices change at some time in the future, we will post the policy changes here as notification and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back to our website periodically.
